{
  "quizInfo": {
    "Subject": "Programming Languages",
    "Term": "Midterms",
    "Title": "04 Handout 1 (ALL)",
    "LastModified": "26 March 2025",
    "Authors": [
      "Alexander Oro"
    ],
    "References": [
      "04 Handout 1"
    ]
  },
  "quizData": [
    {
      "question": "What is the association between an attribute and an entity such as a variable and its type or value?",
      "answer": "binding",
      "choices": [
        "binding",
        "binding time",
        "dynamic type binding",
        "scope"
      ],
      "reference": "Bindings and Scopes",
      "term": "Midterms"
    },
    {
      "question": "What refers to the time a binding takes place, such as compile time or runtime?",
      "answer": "binding time",
      "choices": [
        "binding",
        "binding time",
        "scope",
        "type bindings"
      ],
      "reference": "Bindings and Scopes",
      "term": "Midterms"
    },
    {
      "question": "How is a variable associated with a data type before being referenced in a program?",
      "answer": "type bindings",
      "choices": [
        "type bindings",
        "binding",
        "binding time",
        "shadowing"
      ],
      "reference": "Bindings and Scopes",
      "term": "Midterms"
    },
    {
      "question": "What kind of declaration lists variable names and specifies their particular type?",
      "answer": "explicit declaration",
      "choices": [
        "explicit declaration",
        "implicit declaration",
        "dynamic type binding",
        "scope"
      ],
      "reference": "Bindings and Scopes",
      "term": "Midterms"
    },
    {
      "question": "How is a variable associated with a type through default conventions without a declaration statement?",
      "answer": "implicit declaration",
      "choices": [
        "explicit declaration",
        "implicit declaration",
        "type bindings",
        "scope"
      ],
      "reference": "Bindings and Scopes",
      "term": "Midterms"
    },
    {
      "question": "How does it happen when the variable type is not specified by a declaration statement nor can be determined by the spelling of its name?",
      "answer": "dynamic type binding",
      "choices": [
        "binding time",
        "dynamic type binding",
        "explicit declaration",
        "lifetime and visibility"
      ],
      "reference": "Bindings and Scopes",
      "term": "Midterms"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the range of statements wherein the variable is visible and can be referenced or assigned in a statement?",
      "answer": "scope",
      "choices": [
        "binding",
        "dynamic type binding",
        "explicit declaration",
        "scope"
      ],
      "reference": "Bindings and Scopes",
      "term": "Midterms"
    },
    {
      "question": "What determines where a variable can be used and modified within the code?",
      "answer": "lifetime and visibility",
      "choices": [
        "scope",
        "type bindings",
        "implicit declaration",
        "lifetime and visibility"
      ],
      "reference": "Bindings and Scopes",
      "term": "Midterms"
    },
    {
      "question": "Where are variables accessible from anywhere in the program, including inside functions?",
      "answer": "global scope",
      "choices": [
        "local scope",
        "global scope",
        "enclosing scope",
        "built-in scope"
      ],
      "reference": "Bindings and Scopes",
      "term": "Midterms"
    },
    {
      "question": "What kind of scope refers to variables that are declared inside a function or block and are only accessible within that specific function or block?",
      "answer": "local scope",
      "choices": [
        "global scope",
        "local scope",
        "enclosing scope",
        "built-in scope"
      ],
      "reference": "Bindings and Scopes",
      "term": "Midterms"
    },
    {
      "question": "What refers to the scope of a function that encloses another function?",
      "answer": "enclosing scope",
      "choices": [
        "local scope",
        "global scope",
        "enclosing scope",
        "built-in scope"
      ],
      "reference": "Bindings and Scopes",
      "term": "Midterms"
    },
    {
      "question": "What scope contains all the functions and variables that are built into Python, like print(), len(), and int()?",
      "answer": "built-in scope",
      "choices": [
        "local scope",
        "global scope",
        "enclosing scope",
        "built-in scope"
      ],
      "reference": "Bindings and Scopes",
      "term": "Midterms"
    },
    {
      "question": "What rule does Python follow when looking up variables in nested scopes?",
      "answer": "LEGB Rule",
      "choices": [
        "LEGB Rule",
        "shadowing",
        "global keyword",
        "type bindings"
      ],
      "reference": "Bindings and Scopes",
      "term": "Midterms"
    },
    {
      "question": "What part of the LEGB Rule refers to the innermost scope?",
      "answer": "Local",
      "choices": [
        "Local",
        "Enclosing",
        "Global",
        "Built-in"
      ],
      "reference": "Bindings and Scopes",
      "term": "Midterms"
    },
    {
      "question": "What part of the LEGB Rule refers to enclosing functions like in closures?",
      "answer": "Enclosing",
      "choices": [
        "Local",
        "Enclosing",
        "Global",
        "Built-in"
      ],
      "reference": "Bindings and Scopes",
      "term": "Midterms"
    },
    {
      "question": "What part of the LEGB Rule refers to the module-level scope?",
      "answer": "Global",
      "choices": [
        "Local",
        "Enclosing",
        "Global",
        "Built-in"
      ],
      "reference": "Bindings and Scopes",
      "term": "Midterms"
    },
    {
      "question": "What part of the LEGB Rule refers to Python's built-in objects and functions?",
      "answer": "Built-in",
      "choices": [
        "Local",
        "Enclosing",
        "Global",
        "Built-in"
      ],
      "reference": "Bindings and Scopes",
      "term": "Midterms"
    },
    {
      "question": "What occurs when a local variable has the same name as an outer scope variable and overrides it?",
      "answer": "shadowing",
      "choices": [
        "binding",
        "global keyword",
        "scope",
        "shadowing"
      ],
      "reference": "Bindings and Scopes",
      "term": "Midterms"
    },
    {
      "question": "What keyword is used to modify a global variable inside a function?",
      "answer": "global keyword",
      "choices": [
        "binding",
        "explicit declaration",
        "shadowing",
        "global keyword"
      ],
      "reference": "Bindings and Scopes",
      "term": "Midterms"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the binding time for the type of count?",
      "answer": "at compile time",
      "choices": [
        "at compile time",
        "at compiler design time",
        "at execution time",
        "at runtime"
      ],
      "reference": "Bindings and Scopes",
      "term": "Midterms"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the binding time for the set of possible values of count?",
      "answer": "at compiler design time",
      "choices": [
        "at compile time",
        "at compiler design time",
        "at execution time",
        "at runtime"
      ],
      "reference": "Bindings and Scopes",
      "term": "Midterms"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the binding time for the meaning of the operator symbol?",
      "answer": "at compile time",
      "choices": [
        "at compile time",
        "at compiler design time",
        "at execution time",
        "at runtime"
      ],
      "reference": "Bindings and Scopes",
      "term": "Midterms"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the binding time for internal representation of the literal (int)?",
      "answer": "at compiler design time",
      "choices": [
        "at compile time",
        "at compiler design time",
        "at execution time",
        "at runtime"
      ],
      "reference": "Bindings and Scopes",
      "term": "Midterms"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the binding time for value of the count?",
      "answer": "at execution time",
      "choices": [
        "at compile time",
        "at compiler design time",
        "at execution time",
        "at runtime"
      ],
      "reference": "Bindings and Scopes",
      "term": "Midterms"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is a string of characters used to identify some entity in a program called?",
      "answer": "name",
      "choices": [
        "Function",
        "Variable",
        "name",
        "Class"
      ],
      "reference": "Names",
      "term": "Midterms"
    },
    {
      "question": "What term can be used interchangeably with 'name'?",
      "answer": "identifier",
      "choices": [
        "identifier",
        "function",
        "operator",
        "parser"
      ],
      "reference": "Names",
      "term": "Midterms"
    },
    {
      "question": "What replaced the use of underscores in C-based languages?",
      "answer": "camel notation or camel case",
      "choices": [
        "camel notation or camel case",
        "horse case",
        "snake case",
        "dog case"
      ],
      "reference": "Names",
      "term": "Midterms"
    },
    {
      "question": "What naming style has embedded uppercase letters like myFirstCode?",
      "answer": "camel",
      "choices": [
        "camel",
        "pascal",
        "underscore",
        "proper"
      ],
      "reference": "Names",
      "term": "Midterms"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is a string of characters used to identify some entity in a program?",
      "answer": "name",
      "choices": [
        "Function",
        "Variable",
        "name",
        "Class"
      ],
      "reference": "Names",
      "term": "Midterms"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which languages have no length limit in naming, and all characters are significant?",
      "answer": "Java and C#",
      "choices": [
        "Java and C#",
        "C++",
        "PHP",
        "Perl"
      ],
      "reference": "Names",
      "term": "Midterms"
    },
    {
      "question": "What characters can follow the first letter in programming languages?",
      "answer": "names",
      "choices": [
        "names",
        "class",
        "variables",
        "functions"
      ],
      "reference": "Names",
      "term": "Midterms"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which language does not specify length limits in names, but implementors sometimes do?",
      "answer": "C++",
      "choices": [
        "Java and C#",
        "C++",
        "Perl",
        "Ruby"
      ],
      "reference": "Names",
      "term": "Midterms"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which language requires all variable names to begin with a dollar sign?",
      "answer": "PHP",
      "choices": [
        "Java and C#",
        "C++",
        "PHP",
        "Ruby"
      ],
      "reference": "Names",
      "term": "Midterms"
    },
    {
      "question": "In which language do special characters like $, @, or % specify the type of a variable?",
      "answer": "Perl",
      "choices": [
        "Java and C#",
        "C++",
        "Perl",
        "Ruby"
      ],
      "reference": "Names",
      "term": "Midterms"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which language uses @ and @@ to indicate instance and class variables?",
      "answer": "Ruby",
      "choices": [
        "Java and C#",
        "C++",
        "PHP",
        "Ruby"
      ],
      "reference": "Names",
      "term": "Midterms"
    },
    {
      "question": "What naming style in Python uses lowercase letters and underscores for readability?",
      "answer": "snake case",
      "choices": [
        "camel notation or camel case",
        "horse case",
        "snake case",
        "dog case"
      ],
      "reference": "Names",
      "term": "Midterms"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the naming convention for Function in Python?",
      "answer": "Use lowercase words. Separate words by underscores to improve readability.",
      "choices": [
        "Use lowercase words. Separate words by underscores to improve readability.",
        "Start each word with a capital letter. Do not separate words with underscores.",
        "Use a short, lowercase word or words. Do not separate words with underscores.",
        "Use an uppercase single letter, word, or words. Separate words with underscores to improve readability"
      ],
      "reference": "Names",
      "term": "Midterms"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the naming convention for Variable in Python?",
      "answer": "Use a lowercase single letter, word, or words. Separate words with underscores to improve readability",
      "choices": [
        "Use a lowercase single letter, word, or words. Separate words with underscores to improve readability",
        "Start each word with a capital letter. Do not separate words with underscores.",
        "Use a short, lowercase word or words. Do not separate words with underscores.",
        "Use an uppercase single letter, word, or words. Separate words with underscores to improve readability"
      ],
      "reference": "Names",
      "term": "Midterms"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the naming convention for Class in Python?",
      "answer": "Start each word with a capital letter. Do not separate words with underscores.",
      "choices": [
        "Use a lowercase single letter, word, or words. Separate words with underscores to improve readability",
        "Start each word with a capital letter. Do not separate words with underscores.",
        "Use a short, lowercase word or words. Do not separate words with underscores.",
        "Use an uppercase single letter, word, or words. Separate words with underscores to improve readability"
      ],
      "reference": "Names",
      "term": "Midterms"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the naming convention for Method in Python?",
      "answer": "Use lowercase words. Separate words by underscores to improve readability.",
      "choices": [
        "Use lowercase words. Separate words by underscores to improve readability.",
        "Start each word with a capital letter. Do not separate words with underscores.",
        "Use a short, lowercase word or words. Do not separate words with underscores.",
        "Use an uppercase single letter, word, or words. Separate words with underscores to improve readability"
      ],
      "reference": "Names",
      "term": "Midterms"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the naming convention for Constant in Python?",
      "answer": "Use an uppercase single letter, word, or words. Separate words with underscores to improve readability",
      "choices": [
        "Use lowercase words. Separate words by underscores to improve readability.",
        "Start each word with a capital letter. Do not separate words with underscores.",
        "Use a short, lowercase word or words. Do not separate words with underscores.",
        "Use an uppercase single letter, word, or words. Separate words with underscores to improve readability"
      ],
      "reference": "Names",
      "term": "Midterms"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the naming convention for Module in Python?",
      "answer": "Use a short, lowercase word or words. Separate words with underscores to improve readability.",
      "choices": [
        "Use a short, lowercase word or words. Separate words with underscores to improve readability.",
        "Start each word with a capital letter. Do not separate words with underscores.",
        "Use a short, lowercase word or words. Do not separate words with underscores.",
        "Use an uppercase single letter, word, or words. Separate words with underscores to improve readability"
      ],
      "reference": "Names",
      "term": "Midterms"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the naming convention for Package in Python?",
      "answer": "Use a short, lowercase word or words. Do not separate words with underscores.",
      "choices": [
        "Use a short, lowercase word or words. Separate words with underscores to improve readability.",
        "Start each word with a capital letter. Do not separate words with underscores.",
        "Use a short, lowercase word or words. Do not separate words with underscores.",
        "Use an uppercase single letter, word, or words. Separate words with underscores to improve readability"
      ],
      "reference": "Names",
      "term": "Midterms"
    },
    {
      "question": "What examples follow the function naming convention in Python?",
      "answer": "function, pyt_function",
      "choices": [
        "function, pyt_function",
        "z, var, pyt_variable",
        "Model, PythonClass",
        "class_method, method"
      ],
      "reference": "Names",
      "term": "Midterms"
    },
    {
      "question": "What are some valid examples of variable names in Python?",
      "answer": "z, var, pyt_variable",
      "choices": [
        "CONSTANT, PYTH_CONSTANT, PYTHON_LONG_CONSTANT",
        "z, var, pyt_variable",
        "Model, PythonClass",
        "class_method, method"
      ],
      "reference": "Names",
      "term": "Midterms"
    },
    {
      "question": "What are examples of Pascal case for class names?",
      "answer": "Model, PythonClass",
      "choices": [
        "function, pyt_function",
        "z, var, pyt_variable",
        "Model, PythonClass",
        "class_method, method"
      ],
      "reference": "Names",
      "term": "Midterms"
    },
    {
      "question": "What are examples of method naming in Python?",
      "answer": "class_method, method",
      "choices": [
        "function, pyt_function",
        "z, var, pyt_variable",
        "Model, PythonClass",
        "class_method, method"
      ],
      "reference": "Names",
      "term": "Midterms"
    },
    {
      "question": "What are examples of constants in Python?",
      "answer": "CONSTANT, PYTH_CONSTANT, PYTHON_LONG_CONSTANT",
      "choices": [
        "module.py, python_module.py",
        "package, pythonpackage",
        "CONSTANT, PYTH_CONSTANT, PYTHON_LONG_CONSTANT",
        "function, pyt_function"
      ],
      "reference": "Names",
      "term": "Midterms"
    },
    {
      "question": "What are examples of module file names?",
      "answer": "module.py, python_module.py",
      "choices": [
        "module.py, python_module.py",
        "CONSTANT, PYTH_CONSTANT, PYTHON_LONG_CONSTANT",
        "z, var, pyt_variable",
        "function, pyt_function"
      ],
      "reference": "Names",
      "term": "Midterms"
    },
    {
      "question": "What are examples of Python package names?",
      "answer": "package, pythonpackage",
      "choices": [
        "module.py, python_module.py",
        "package, pythonpackage",
        "z, var, pyt_variable",
        "CONSTANT, PYTH_CONSTANT, PYTHON_LONG_CONSTANT"
      ],
      "reference": "Names",
      "term": "Midterms"
    },
    {
      "question": "What naming style starts each word with a capital letter?",
      "answer": "pascal case",
      "choices": [
        "pascal case",
        "snake case",
        "camel case",
        "brief case"
      ],
      "reference": "Names",
      "term": "Midterms"
    },
    {
      "question": "How are words that separate the syntactic parts of programs identified?",
      "answer": "special words",
      "choices": [
        "special words",
        "reserved words",
        "names",
        "identifiers"
      ],
      "reference": "Names",
      "term": "Midterms"
    },
    {
      "question": "What are words in most programming languages that cannot be used as names?",
      "answer": "reserved words",
      "choices": [
        "special words",
        "reserved words",
        "names",
        "identifiers"
      ],
      "reference": "Names",
      "term": "Midterms"
    },
    {
      "question": "What language treats special words as keywords rather than reserved words?",
      "answer": "Fortran",
      "choices": [
        "Fortran",
        "Java and C#",
        "C++",
        "COBOL"
      ],
      "reference": "Names",
      "term": "Midterms"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which language includes 300 reserved words that can limit programmer choices?",
      "answer": "COBOL",
      "choices": [
        "COBOL",
        "Fortran",
        "Java and C#",
        "C++"
      ],
      "reference": "Names",
      "term": "Midterms"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is an abstraction of a memory cell or cells in programming?",
      "answer": "Variables",
      "choices": [
        "Variables",
        "Class",
        "Binding",
        "Scopes"
      ],
      "reference": "Names",
      "term": "Midterms"
    },
    {
      "question": "What can be made up of letters, numbers, and underscores in a program?",
      "answer": "Variable Names",
      "choices": [
        "Variable Names",
        "Variable Address",
        "Variable Type",
        "Variable Value"
      ],
      "reference": "Names",
      "term": "Midterms"
    },
    {
      "question": "What are the most common names in programs used to reference changing values?",
      "answer": "Variable Names",
      "choices": [
        "Variable Names",
        "Variable Address",
        "Variable Type",
        "Variable Value"
      ],
      "reference": "Names",
      "term": "Midterms"
    },
    {
      "question": "What acts as a numerical identifier that allows the program to access and manipulate the data held by a variable?",
      "answer": "Variable Address",
      "choices": [
        "Variable Scope",
        "Variable Address",
        "Variable Type",
        "Variable Value"
      ],
      "reference": "Names",
      "term": "Midterms"
    },
    {
      "question": "What identifies the unique memory location of a variable?",
      "answer": "Variable Address",
      "choices": [
        "Variable Names",
        "Variable Address",
        "Variable Type",
        "Variable Value"
      ],
      "reference": "Names",
      "term": "Midterms"
    },
    {
      "question": "What determines the range and valid operations of a variable?",
      "answer": "Variable Type",
      "choices": [
        "Variable Scope",
        "Variable Lifetime",
        "Variable Type",
        "Variable Value"
      ],
      "reference": "Names",
      "term": "Midterms"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the content held by a memory cell associated with a variable?",
      "answer": "Variable Value",
      "choices": [
        "Variable Scope",
        "Variable Lifetime",
        "Variable Type",
        "Variable Value"
      ],
      "reference": "Names",
      "term": "Midterms"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is required when a variable name appears on the right side of an assignment statement?",
      "answer": "Variable Value",
      "choices": [
        "Variable Scope",
        "Variable Address",
        "Variable Type",
        "Variable Value"
      ],
      "reference": "Names",
      "term": "Midterms"
    },
    {
      "question": "What defines how long a variable retains value in memory?",
      "answer": "Variable Lifetime",
      "choices": [
        "Variable Scope",
        "Variable Lifetime",
        "Variable Type",
        "Variable Value"
      ],
      "reference": "Names",
      "term": "Midterms"
    },
    {
      "question": "What defines the part of the program where a variable can be accessed?",
      "answer": "Variable Scope",
      "choices": [
        "Variable Scope",
        "Variable Address",
        "Variable Type",
        "Variable Lifetime"
      ],
      "reference": "Names",
      "term": "Midterms"
    }
  ]
}